discoverboating.com 2018-12-19

# Privacy Policy | Discover Boating

### Privacy Policy

May 17, 2018

Your privacy is a priority for Grow Boating, Inc., NFP, which operates the Discover Boating website (Grow Boating), and we go to great lengths to protect it. We recognize your need to protect and manage any personal information you share with us. Please take a moment to read this privacy policy to learn more about our information practices, including what type of information is gathered, how the information is used and for what purposes, to whom we disclose the information, and how we safeguard your personal information. Specifically, this privacy policy covers the following topics:

  * _Children’s Privacy Statement_
  * _Information Collection and Use_
  * _Newsletter_
  * _Choice_
  * _Website Traffic_
  * _Cookies_
  * _Information Sharing_
  * _Data Security_
  * _Managing Personal Information_
  * _Data Retention _
  * _Data Transfer_
  * _External Links_
  * _Notification of Changes_
  * _Acceptance of Privacy Policy Terms_
  * _Contact Information_

**Children’s Privacy Statement**

The website and our services and products are not directed toward children under the age of 16. We do not knowingly collect information from children. If we become aware that a child has provided us with information without parental consent, that information will be deleted from our records. 

**Information Collection and Use**

This privacy policy applies to information that Grow Boating collects (i) on this website, (ii) through other platforms used in connection with the services and products that we provide, and (iii) by telephone, email, text message, letter, or other methods of communication. When you use our services or products, we collect information provided voluntarily and information collected automatically, as described in detail below. Please note that you may decline to share your personal information with us, in which case we may not be able to provide you with certain services or products.

There are situations in which your personal information may help us give you better service. For example, we may ask for your personal information when you order a Free "How to Get Started with Boating" DVD, sign up for the Wave! Newsletter, get Free Magazine Subscriptions or fill out a form to receive brochures and materials. At such times, we may collect personal information relevant to the situation, such as your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, and contact preferences. In some cases, we also ask you to provide information for market research purposes to gain a better understanding of our customers and thus provide more valuable service.

Grow Boating uses the information that we collect to provide our services and products and to operate our business. We may use and store such information for legitimate and lawful business purposes, for example, in order to: 

  * provide a service or product you requested;
  * analyze and evaluate customer needs and interests, and improve the customer experience;
  * notify you of Grow Boating official business, news, activities, programs, events, meetings, conferences, services, products, and benefits;
  * respond to communications and inquiries that you send to us; 
  * promote the safety and security of our services; and 
  * for other legitimate and lawful business purposes.

For individuals located in the European Economic Area, we rely on multiple legal bases to collect, use, share, or otherwise process your personal data, including that: 

  * you have given consent, which you may withdraw at any time; 
  * it is necessary for us to perform a contract with you; 
  * it is necessary for us to comply with legal obligations; 
  * it is necessary for our or a third party’s legitimate interests; 
  * it is necessary for us to perform a task in the public interest or for our official functions; and/or 
  * it is necessary to protect someone’s life. 

To the extent we rely on our legitimate interests as a legal basis to collect, use, share, or otherwise process your personal data, those interests include: providing a product or service you requested; analyzing and evaluating customer needs and interests, and improving the customer experience; notifying you of Grow Boating official business, news, activities, programs, events, meetings, conferences, services, products, and benefits; responding to communications and inquiries that you send to us; and promoting the safety and security of our services.

**Newsletter**

If you wish to subscribe to our Wave! Newsletter, we ask for contact information such as your name and email address. While we cannot prevent users from signing up other individuals to receive the newsletter, out of respect for our users’ privacy, we provide a way for you to opt out of these communications if you no longer wish to receive them. Please see the _Choice_ section below.

In some of our email messages we use a “click-through URL” linked to content on the DiscoverBoating.com website. When a customer clicks one of these URLs, they pass through a web server before arriving at the destination web page. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked simply avoid clicking text or graphic links in the email.

In addition, we sometimes use pixel tags - tiny graphic images - to tell us what parts of our website customers have visited or to measure the effectiveness of searches customers perform on our website. Pixel tags also enable us to send email messages in a format customers can read. And they tell us whether emails have been opened to assure that we're only sending messages that are of interest to you.

**Choice**

If you no longer wish to receive our Wave! Newsletter or other email communications that you previously requested from us, you may opt out of continuing to receive such communications by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link that appears at the bottom of each email or by sending an email to [support@discoverboating.com](mailto:support@discoverboating.com).

If you no longer wish to receive the communications from third parties that you previously opted in to, as set forth in the _Information Sharing_ section below, when requesting products or information from our website, such as the Free How to Get Started in Boating DVD or the Boat Selector Tool, you may opt out of continuing to receive such communications by sending an email to [support@discoverboating.com](mailto:support@discoverboating.com) or by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed in the _Contact Information_ section below.  

**Website Traffic**

As most websites do, the DiscoverBoating.com website gathers certain information automatically and stores it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which DOES NOT identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. This helps us to determine how best to provide useful information to customers and to understand which parts of our websites and Internet services are of most interest to them.

**Cookies**

As is standard practice on many corporate websites, DiscoverBoating.com uses “cookies” and other technologies to help us understand which parts of our websites are the most popular, where our visitors are going, and how much time they spend there. We also use cookies and other technologies to make sure that our online advertising is bringing customers to our website. And we use cookies to customize your experience and provide greater convenience each time you interact with us.

**Information Sharing**

We take your privacy very seriously. To help us provide superior service, your personal information may be shared with legal entities related to or affiliated with Grow Boating, which will safeguard it in accordance with this privacy policy. There are also times when it may be necessary for Grow Boating to make certain personal information about you available to third-party companies that we have a strategic relationship with or that perform work for us to provide products and services to you on our behalf. These companies may help us process information, fulfill customer orders, deliver products to you, manage and enhance customer data, provide customer service, or conduct customer research or satisfaction surveys. These companies are also obligated to protect your personal information in accordance with this privacy policy. Without such information being made available, it would be very difficult to have products delivered to you, receive customer service, provide us feedback, or access certain services, offers, and content on the DiscoverBoating.com website.

You may provide us your contact information when requesting products or information from our website, such as the Free How to Get Started in Boating DVD or the Boat Selector Tool, at which time you may opt in to our disclosure of your contact information to third parties, including companies and organizations participating in or providing products and services to the recreational boating industry, by checking the box at the bottom of the applicable form indicating “I would like to be contacted by manufacturers and dealers.” If you no longer wish to receive such communications, you may update your preferences as set forth in the _Choice_ section above.  

Additionally, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law when we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, law enforcement or government agency inquiry or investigation, court order, subpoena or other legal process served on Grow Boating. We also may use and disclose information about you to establish or exercise our legal rights, to assert and defend against legal claims, or if we believe such disclosure is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take other action regarding actual or suspected illegal or fraudulent activities or potential threats to the physical safety or well-being of any person.

If all or part of Grow Boating is merged into or otherwise transferred to another entity, we may transfer the personal information you provided to us to such entity as part of that transaction.

**Data Security**

Grow Boating takes reasonable precautions to protect your information, including administrative, technical, and physical security measures, to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line. However, please be aware that no method of electronic transmission is completely infallible, and we cannot guarantee its absolute safety. You can help us by also taking precautions to protect your personal data when you are on the Internet. Change your passwords often using a combination of letters and numbers, and make sure you use a secure web browser.

If users have any questions about data security, please send an email to [support@discoverboating.com](mailto:support@discoverboating.com).

**Managing Personal Information**

Grow Boating takes your privacy and the protection of your personal information seriously, and we will provide you with reasonable access to and control of the personal information that you have provided to us. If your personally identifiable information (such as your phone, email or postal address) changes, or if you no longer wish to receive our services, please contact us to correct, update or delete/deactivate your personally identifiable information by sending an email to [support@discoverboating.com](mailto:support@discoverboating.com) or by telephone or postal mail using the contact information provided in the _Contact Information_ section below.

For individuals located in the European Economic Area, you may have additional rights concerning your personal data, such as to access, obtain a copy of, correct, or delete that information or to withdraw your consent or object to the collection, use, sharing, or other processing of that information. To make any request with respect to your personal information, please contact us by sending an email to [support@discoverboating.com](mailto:support@discoverboating.com) or by telephone or postal mail using the contact information provided in the _Contact Information_ section below.

**Data Retention **

Grow Boating retains your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected as set forth in this privacy policy, unless otherwise required by law. We will retain and use information as necessary to comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes, enforce agreements, and as otherwise set forth in this privacy policy. 

**Data Transfer**

If you are visiting the website from outside the United States, please be aware that you are sending information, including personal data, to the United States where our servers are located. That information may then be transferred within the United States or to other countries outside the United States other than your country of residence. Countries other than your country of residence, including the United States, may have data privacy and protection laws that differ from, and potentially provide less protection than, the applicable laws in your country of residence. Our collection, use, sharing, and other processing of your personal information will at all times be governed by this privacy policy. 

To the extent that Grow Boating may be deemed to have transferred personal data outside of the European Economic Area, we rely on multiple legal bases for doing so. For individuals located in the European Economic Area, by providing your personal information, you consent to our use of it in accordance with this privacy policy, including the transfer of your information across international boundaries to jurisdictions anywhere in the world as permitted by applicable law. In addition, we will obtain separate consent from individuals located in the European Economic Area in connection with the provision of certain services that involve the transfer of personal data. Finally, when transferring the personal data of individuals located in the European Economic Area, we will use the standard contractual data protection clauses adopted by the European Commission, which provide safeguards for the transfer of such data, in connection with the provision of certain services that involve such transfers.

**External Links**

DiscoverBoating.com contains links to other websites. Please be aware that Grow Boating is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites and hereby disclaims any liability or responsibility in connection with such linked websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our website and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website.

**Notification of Changes**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

If, however, we are going to use users’ personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our website notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice, we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

**Acceptance of Privacy Policy Terms**

Using the DiscoverBoating.com website indicates your acceptance of our privacy policy. Your continued visits to the DiscoverBoating.com website after changes are posted to this policy will signify your acceptance of those changes. 

**Contact Information**

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact:

GrowBoating, Inc., NFP  
231 S. LaSalle Street, Suite 2050  
Chicago, IL 60604  
United States of America  
Phone: (312) 946-6200  
Email: [support@discoverboating.com](mailto:support@discoverboating.com)
